A Finding Aid to the James D. Smillie and Smillie family papers, 1853-1957, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- James David Smillie papers, 1853-1917; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 4.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-7
  - Diaries, 1865-1909; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    Hart, Maria Theresa Gorsuch: 1866 Jan 2; 1867 Apr 22, Oct 24; 1870 Aug 2; 1874 Jan 8; 1875 Mar 23
    Hart, William: 1867 Feb 19, Oct 28, Nov 1, Nov 23; 1868 Jan 31, Feb 25, Nov 2, Nov 12, Dec 21; 1869 Nov 15; 1870 Jan 31, Feb 1, Apr 29, Jun 7, Nov 10, Dec 13; 1871 Jan 31, Feb 3, Mar 14, APr 4, Apr 25, May 1, May 9, May 12, May 15, Nov 2; 1872 Feb 1, Feb 6, Nov 9, Nov 12, Nov 25, Dec 10; 1873 Jan 9, Feb 5, Mar 29, Nov 3; 1874 Apr 30; 1875 Mar 20, Apr 3; 1876 Feb 11
    Hayes [Hays], William Jacob: 1869 Mar 31, Dec 18
    Heade, Martin Johnson: 1869 Sep 13; 1870 Apr 29, Jun 9, Dec 30
    Hennessy, William John: 1870 APr 29
    Henry Edward Lamson: 1880 Dec 20
    Hepburn, William: 1875 Jan 28
    Hetzel, George: 1878 May 28
    Hicks, Thomas: 1876 May 1
    Hill, John William: 1876 Apr 11
    Hodgkins: 1868 Sep 14
    Holbertson, Wakeman H.: 1873 Feb 1
    Homer, Winslow: 1875 Feb 6; 1878 Mar 15
    Howland, Alfred C.: 1872 Jul 10; 1873 May 1
    Hubbard, Richard William: 1867 Feb 19; 1875 Feb 8, Apr 9, May 22
    Huntington, Daniel P.: 1868 Apr 1; 1869 Jan 29, May 10; 1872 Mar 14; 1876 Feb 16, may 1; 1877 Fan 9; 1878 Mar 4
    Innes, George: 1868 May 1, May 4; 1879 Mar 14
    Jefferson, Joseph: 1870 Nov 4, Nov 9
    Johns, "Of Pittsburgh": 1871 Jan 15
    Johnson, David: 1874 Mar 23; 1875 Feb 4
    Johnson, Eastman: 1868 Apr 1; 1869 Jan 29, Apr 4; 1878 Aug 4, Aug 24, Aug 25, Aug 27, Aug 26; 1879 Feb 7; 1880 Jul 21
    Johnson, Samuel Frost: 1870 Jun 1; 1871 Jan 4; 1873 Jan 8, Apr 8; 1876 Dec 14
    King, [no first name]: 1871 Jul 29, Aug 9; 1873 Jan 3
    Kensett, John Frederick: 1866 Feb 21; 1868 Jan 29; 1870 Nov 10; 1872 Apr 23; 1873 Mar 13
    Kittell, Nicholas Biddle: 1870 Feb 8, Apr 9; 1874 Jun 22
    Knowlton, Miss: 1879 Aug 13
    Knudsen: 1870 Mar 10
    Kuntze, Edward J.: 1868 May 8, Jun 9; 1869 Apr 15, Oct 19; 1870 Mar 10, Apr 10
    La Farge, John: 1869 Nov 22, Nov 25; 1870 Apr 29
    Lambdin, George C.: 1868 Jan 31, Aug 13, Aug 15
    Lang, Louis: 1871 Nov 16
    Lawrie, Alexander: 1869 Nov 15; 1873 Oct 2; 1874 Mar 24
    Leutze, Emanuel Gottlieb: 1866 Feb 21
    Linton, William James: 1870 Apr 29; 1873 Nov 3; 1874 Jan 13
    Loop Henry Augustus: 1865 Nov 29, Nov 30, Dec 25; 1866 Feb 7; 1869 Jan 3, Oct 14
    McEntee, Jervis: 1868 Jan 18; 1869 Dec 18; 1876 May 1, Jun 23; 1878 Apr 25
    Magrath, William: 1870 Aug 8, Dec 19; 1871 Jan 16; 1874 Jun 6; 1875 Feb 1, Nov 6; 1876 Dec 21, Dec 22, Dec 26; 1877 Mar 28; 1878 Jan 24, Jan 29, Mar 20
    Martin, Charles: 1870 May 18
    Martin, Homer Dodge: 1870 Jun 17
    Miller, Charles Henry: 1874 Mar 2; 1877 Dec 5; 1878 Apr 8
    Moore, Charles Herbert: 1868 Mar 11
    Moran, Edward: 1873 Apr 25, Nov 1; 1876 Mar 14; 1880 Mar 18
    Moran, Thomas: 1873 Dec 7; 1874 May 21; 1876 Apr 6
    Morse, Samuel F. B.: 1869 Mar 13; 1870 Apr 21
    Mulvaney, John: 875 Jul 15, Sep 3
    Nast, Thomas: 1873 Feb 9, Feb 17
    Nehlig, Victor: 1870 Apr 29, Dec 27; 1871 Jan 19
    Newman, Henry Roderick: 1870 Feb 17; 1873 Jan 9
    Nicoll, James Craig: 1867 Oct 6; 1869 Dec 20; 1870 Feb 1, Apr 6, May 3, May 7, Dec 30; 1871 Jan 9, Jan 14, Mar 20, Oct 21; 1872 Feb 26, Dec 1, Dec 11; 1873 Jan 6, Jan 15, Feb 3, Oct 31, Nov 1, Nov 4, Nov 28, Dec 1, Dec 2, Dec 4, Dec 9, Dec 23, Dec 29; 1874 Jan 17, Jan 21, Jan 30, Feb 2, Feb 3, Feb 4, Feb 5, Feb 12, Feb 13, Apr 28, May 14, May 16, May 19, May 26, Jun 24, Oct 3, Oct 25, Nov 27, Dec 3, Dec 8; 1875 Jan 6, Jan 27, Feb 3, Feb 8, Feb 17, Mar 3, Mar 15, Mar 19, Mar 22, Apr 5, Apr 9, Apr 28, Apr 29, May 5, May 14, Jun 18, Jul 3, Nov 2, Nov 3, Nov 26, Nov 26, Nov 30, Dec 1, Dec 14, Dec 17, Dec 20, Dec 21; 1876 Jan 21, Feb 14, Mar 1, Mar 14, Mar 20, Mar 29, Apr 3, Apr 7, Apr 8, Sep 3, Nov 20, Dec 16, Dec 18, Dec 22, Dec 28; 1877 Jan 2, Jan 11, Feb 6, Feb 15, Feb 19, Feb 27, Mar 1, Mar 6, Mar 9, May 10, Jun 20, Nov 14, Nov 15, Nov 24, Dec 14, Dec 18; 1878 Jan 26, Feb 13, Mar 6, Mar 12, Mar 20, Apr 4, May 9, May 17, May 17, Jul 1, Jul 2, Nov 20, Dec 11, Dec 28; 1879 Mar 1, Mar 10, Jul 19, Nov 13, Dec 16; 1880 Mar 8, Apr 12, Apr 30
    Norton, Henry: 1874 Jan 10
    Ogilvie, Clinton: 1868 Apr 13, Apr 30, Jul 13; 1869 Dec 22; 1871 Jan 7; 1872 Apr 1; 1873 Mar 4; 1877 Jan 2; 1879 Apr 21
    Ordway, Albert T.: 1868 Jan 18
    Page, William: 1871 Nov 9, Nov 23, Dec 12; 1872 May 9, Nov 22; 1875 Feb 3
    Parton, Ernest: 1871 Jan 31; 1872 Feb 5; 1874 Jan 31; 1880 Dec 20
    Perry, Enoch Wood: 1868 Jan 31; 1869 Nov 10; 1870 Dec 13; 1871 Nov 23, Nov 27, Dec 5; 1872 Jan 27, Feb 5, May 9, Nov 20; 1874 Feb 6, Jun 24; 1875 Feb 6, Apr 9; 1877 Feb 9, May 2
    Porter: 1871 Sep 1
    Reed, T. F.: 1868 Mar 30, Apr 18, Jun 12; 1869 Feb 21
    Reinhart, Charles: 1877 Dec 18; 1878 Feb 22, Mar 4, Apr 8
    Reinhart, Benjamin OR William: 1870 Apr 13; 1871 Nov 14
    Richards, Thomas Addison: 1868 Apr 1, Apr 17, Jun 2, Jul 3, Nov 12; 1871 Nov 20; 1872 Mar 11, Nov 25, Dec 10; 1873 Feb 20, Dec 5, Dec 9; 1874 Jan 6, Jan 12, Apr 6, Apr 21; 1875 Dec 14
    Richards, William Trost: 1869 Mar 13; Apr 14, May 4m Nov 23, Nov 24, Dec 7; 1870 May 5; 1871 Jan 17, Mar 20; 1872 Feb 8, Dec 1; 1873 Jan 29, Mar 20, Jun 3, Jun 5, Jun 6; 1874 Apr 8; 1875 Jan 3, Feb 24, Feb 25, Mar 29, May 31, Nov 23; 1876 Jan 10, Apr 21, May 4, Oct 22, Oct 26, Oct 27; 1877 Jul 26; Dec 19; 1878 Mar 4
    Richards, [no first name]: 1871; 1874; 1875 Jan 28
    Richardson, Cora: 1873 Dec 12, Dec 13, Dec 22
    Rimmer, William: 1870 Dec 6, Dec 13, Dec 21; 1872 Jan 4, Feb 1, Feb 8, Feb 15, Feb 22, Mar 29
    Ritchie, Alexander Hay: 1868 Apr 17, May 12, May 20, May 23, May 25, May 26, May 28, Jun 15, Jun 22, Jun 24, Jun 25, Jun 26, Jun 27, Jun 30, Jul 1, Jul 2, Jul 3, Jul 10
    Robbins, Horace Wolcott: 1869 Mar 11, Nov 22, Dec 15; 1870 Dec 12; 1873; 1874 Apr 18, Dec 16; 1875 Nov 26, Nov 30; 1876 Jan 14, Jan 17, Mar 1, Mar 12, Mar 16, Nov 20, Dec 18; 1877 Apr 18, Apr 22, Jul 26, Jul 27, Nov 8; 1878 Jan 10, Jan 18, Feb 23, Feb 24, Mar 9, Mar 20, May 1; 1879 Dec 11, Dec 12; 1880 Feb 28
    Rogers, John: 1870 Nov 4; 1871 Feb 5, Mar 10, Apr 14, Dec 8; 1872 May 6; 1873 Dec 29; 1875 Mar 26, Apr 4, Nov 25, Dec 8, Dec 19; 1876; 1877 Apr 1
    Rondel, Louis: 1870 Mar 3, Mar 30, Dec 12
    Rondell, Frederick: 1867 Nov 28; 1869 May 29
    Rood, Prof.: 1869 Feb 7; 1871 Feb 10
    Ryder, Albert Pinkham: 1872 Jan 12, Feb 22, Mar 14, Mar 18, Mar 28
    Satterlee, Walter: 1873 Apr 19, Nov 3; 1874 Dec 9, Dec 16; 1876 Jan 14, Mar 7; 1877 Nov 8; 1878 Feb 23
    Scott, Julian: 1867 Feb 19; 1870 Apr 29
    Shattuck, Aaron Draper: 1867 Feb 19, Nov 23; 1871 Nov 16, Nov 23; 1872 Feb 22
    Shirlaw, Walter: 1870 Feb 17; 1878 Mar 11, Apr 8; 1880 Mar 4
    Shortleffe, Roswell Morse: 1869 Aug 23, Aug 27, Aug 30; 1870 Aug 13, Aug 23, Aug 31, Sep 20-22; 1872 Feb 28, Mar 8; 1873 Mar 18; 1874 Mar 23, Dec 6; 1875 Jan 25l 1877 Jan 7, Mar 20, Mar 28, Jun 23, Nov 25; 1878 Jun 4, Dec 20; 1879 Feb 19, Apr 8, May 23, Nov 18; 1880 Apr 14
    Silva, Francis A.: 1874 Jan 13, Feb 2, Jun 1, Jun 16, Jun 17; 1875 Jan 25, Jan 26, Jan 27, Feb 1, Dec 17; 1876 Feb 7, Feb 28, Mar 14, Dec 22, Dec 26; 1877 Mar 30; 1878 Mar 5, Mar 20
    Slade, Helen (?): 1870 Mar 10
    Smith, Francis Hopkinson: 1873 Jan 28, Jan 29; 1874 Feb 22, Dec 6, Dec 10; 1875 Jan 14, Jan 27, Feb 3, Mar 4, Mar 5, Mar 7, Mar 15-20, Mar 20, Mar 24, Apr 1, May 3, May 13, Nov 3, Nov 7, NOv 16, Nov 26, Dec 1, Dec 17, Dec 20; 1876 Jan 12, Jan 17, Jan 26, Feb 8, Feb 11, Mar 1, Mar 26, Jul 4, Dec 23; 1877 Jan 7, Jan 16, Feb 8, Feb 9, Feb 16, Mar 16, Mar 18; 1878 Jan 16, Feb 13, Mar 12, Mar 14, Mar 18, Mar 20, Apr 30, Dec 20; 1880 Jan 21, Oct 8
    Smith, Thomas Lochlan: 1871 Jan 7; 1877 Nov 29
    Symington: 1877 Feb 9; 1878 Mar 20
    Tait, Arthur F.: 1868 Jan 17, Dec 7; 1869 Nov 15; 1870 Feb 5
    Thayer, "Prof": 1879 Aug 26
    Thompson, Launt: 1873 Feb 19
    Thompson, [no first name]: 1873; 1875 Mar 20; 1876 Mar 7; 1877 Nov 8; 1878 Feb 19
    Thurston, Frank: 1872 Apr 9
    Tiffany, Louis Comfort: 1867 Jun 27, Sep 5, Nov 29; 1868 Aug 12, Aug 15, Aug 31, Sep 1, Sep 1, Sep 6, Sep 10, Nov 7, Dec 16; 1869 Mar 29, Apr 6, Apr 12, APr 26, Aug 16, Aug 18, Aug 21, Aug 23, Aug 24, Aug 26, Oct 26, Oct 27, Nov 15, Nov 22; 1870 Jan 22, Mar 10, May 9, Jun 6, Jun 30, Jul 2-5, Jul 15; 1871 Feb 11, Feb 15, Mar 13, Apr 22, Nov 23, Dec 30; 1872 Jan 8, Jan 10, Jan 17, Feb 2, Feb 16, Mar 11, Mar 14, Apr 8, May 17, Nov 12, Nov 14, Nov 25, Dec 9, Dec 19, Dec 11; 1873 Jan 1, Jan 9, Jan 17, Jan 28, Feb 1, Feb 3, Feb 7, Feb 8, Mar 10, Mar 29, Nov 3, Dec 4, Dec 9, Dec 27; 1874 Jan 15, Jan 17, Jan 20, Feb 2, Feb 3, Feb 4, Feb 11, Mar 2, Apr 14, May 5; 1875 May 18, May 21, Nov 4, Nov 7, NOv 8, Dec 16, Dec 21; 1876 Jan 29, Nov 14, Dec 22; 1877 Mar 8, May 7, Jun 4, Jun 13, Oct 26, Nov 8, Nov 21; 1878 Jan 18, Feb 25, Mar 2, Mar 5, Mar 8, Mar 20, Apr 6, Nov 18; 1879 Jan 16, Feb 7, Mar 3, Apr 22, Dec 8; 1880 Jan 3, Mar 8, Apr 12, May 8, Nov 10
    Townley: 1871 Jan 16, Apr 18
    Troll, Mrs.: 1870 Aug 8; 1874 Dec 16
    Vaini, Pietro: 1874 Jan 7, Apr 15, Jun 17
    Van Elten, Kruseman: 1867 Feb 6, Oct 6
    Vedder, Elihu: 1869 Jan 27, Mar 17
    Verplanck, Delancy: 1869 Jan 25, Jan 26, Nov 10; 1872 Feb 21, Jun 24, Jul 9, Jul 10; 1873 Dec 29; 1874 Feb 25
    Waller: 1880 Feb 25, Feb 27, Mar 26
    Walters, Josephine: 1871 Mar 6, Dec 30
    Ward, Charles Caleb: 1871 Feb 4
    Ward, E. M.: 1877 Jan 19, Apr 2
    Ward, J. Q. A.: 1866 Dec 3; 1867 Feb 6, Feb 19; 1868 Jul 24; 1869 Jan 29, Jan 30, Feb 8; 1870 May 9; 1871 Jan 4, Nov 2, Nov 23; 1873 Nov 25, Dec 8; 1874 Jan 22, Mar 2, Mar 28; 1876 Feb 16; 1877 Nov 27; 1879 May 6
    Warren, Andrew W.: 1870 May 4, May 30, Jun 7
    Weir, John F.: 1878 May 1
    Weir, J. Alden: 1880 Mar 3
    Wenzler, Henry Anton: 1868 Mar 6, Apr 13; 1870 Nov 5, Nov 14; 1871 Jan 19, Apr 4, Apr 10
    West: Feb 6
    White, Edwin: 1868 Apr 1
    Whittredge, Thomas Worthington: 1865 Mar 28; 1868 Mar 14m Apr 1; 1869 Jan 29, Dec 18; 1871 Jun 2-9; 1874 Jan 8, Jan 22, Jun 24; 1875 Sep 17, Sep 29, Nov 12, Nov 30; 1876 Apr 14, Apr 24, Apr 25, Apr 26, Apr 27, May 3, May 5, May 8; 1880 Apr 8
    Williams, Isaac (?): 1869 May 5; 1876 Apr 27, May 3
    Willis, William H.: 1869 Jan 14
    Wilmarth, Lemuel Everett: 1874 Dec 4; 1877 Nov 22; 1878 Jan 14, Mar 4
    Wood, George Bacon: 1868 Aug 1; 1869 Aug 14, Oct 15; 1873 Apr 23
    Wood, Thomas Hosmer: 1870 Mar 4, Mar 18; 1871 Jan 19
    Wood, Thomas Waterman: 1869 Jan 17, Feb 2; 1870; 1872; 1873 Mar 29; 1874 May 12; 1876 Mar 1; 1877 Feb 3, Feb 5, May 2, Jun 1, Jun 4, Jun 6; 1878 Jan 2, Jan 7, Jan 14, Jan 21, Jan 29, Feb 19, Mar 4, Mar 9, Mar 20, May 15, May 17, May 18, May 29; 1879 Feb 10, Mar 1, Jun 14, Jun 19; 1880 Jan 25, Jan 31, Dec 29
    Woodward, Laura (?): 1872 Jan 22; 1873 May 20, Dec 2, Dec 13, Dec 18; 1874 Mar 7, Mar 16, Apr 11, Apr 17, May 20, MAy 25, Jun 11, Jun 17, Jun 24, Nov 13, Nov 16, Dec 22; 1875 Jan 12, Jan 21, Jan 22, Feb 3, Feb 25, Mar 1, Apr 12, Dec 3, Dec 24; 1876 Jan 9, Jan 25, May 17, May 19; 1877 Nov 8; 1879 Aug 28
    Woolsey, E. J.: 1868 Apr 1
    Wyatt, Alexander Helwig: 1869 Jan 9, Jan 17, Feb 3, Nov 15; 1870 Feb 4, Apr 26, May 28, Aug 8, Sep 18, Sep 20-22; 1872 MAr 8, Dec 10; 1873 Feb 5, Dec 27; 1874 Apr 30; 1877 Nov 1; 1878 Aug 17, Aug 25, Nov 22, Dec 22; 1879 Jan 26, Feb 25, Mar 12, Nov 12
    Yale, Leroy Milton: 1869 Jan 13; 1870 Oct 29, Nov 29, Nov 30, Dec 13; 1871 May 15, Nov 1; 1875 Feb 26, Feb 27, Mar 8, Mar 9, Apr 12, Mar 30, May 2, May 11, Jun 27, Oct 23, Oct 29; 1878 Jan 11, Mar 11, Mar 13; 1879 May 31, Jun 3
    Young, James Harvey: 1868 Apr 8
    - Daily Diary, 1865; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Daily Diary, 1866; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Daily Diary, 1867; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Daily Diary, 1868; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Daily Diary, 1869; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Daily Diary, 1870; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Daily Diary, 1871; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Daily Diary, 1872; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Daily Diary, 1873; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Daily Diary, 1874; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Daily Diary, 1875; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Daily Diary, 1876; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Daily Diary, 1877; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Daily Diary, 1878; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Daily Diary, 1879; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Daily Diary, 1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Daily Diary, 1881; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Daily Diary, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1883; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Daily Diary, 1884; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Daily Diary, 1885; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Daily Diary, 1886; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Daily Diary, 1887; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Daily Diary, 1888; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Daily Diary, 1889; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Daily Diary, 1890; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Daily Diary, 1891; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Daily Diary, 1892; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Daily Diary, 1893; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Daily Diary, 1894; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1895; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Daily Diary, 1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Daily Diary, 1897; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Daily Diary, 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Daily Diary, 1899; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Daily Diary, 1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Daily Diary, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Daily Diary, 1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Daily Diary, 1903; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Daily Diary, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Daily Diary, 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Daily Diary, 1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Daily Diary, 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Daily Diary, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Materials Tucked into Diaries, Archival Resource Key (Box 4)
      - Biographical Sketches and Writings, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Ephemera, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Addresses and Notes, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Calendar Fragments, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Financial Statements, Lists of Expenses, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Price Lists, Bills, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Insurance Documents, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Loan Agreements, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Receipts, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Prescriptions, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Prescriptions, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Prescriptions, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Rental Payments, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Voting Tallies for National Academy of Design, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Lists of Works of Art, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Lists of Works of Art, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Note, Found in Pocket of Uncle, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Writings, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Writings, 1881-1886; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Notes, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Business Cards, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Business Cards, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Business Cards, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Calling Cards, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Calling Cards, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Calling Cards, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Clippings, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Clippings, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Clippings, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Admission Tickets, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Admission Tickets, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Playbills and Invitations, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Playbills, 1897-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Sketches and Silhouettes, 1865-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Sketches, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Sketches, Landscape Sketch for a House, 1881-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Photographs, 1864-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
        Photographs of James David Smillie and William J. Turrell.
  - Scrapbook, circa 1850s-1900; 1.4; Archival Resource Key
    The scrapbook contains clippings, publications with etchings, and reproductions of prints. Although not all are labeled, many of the clippings were written by or concern James D. Smillie.
    - Scrapbook of Clippings and Reproductions of Works of Art, circa 1850s-1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material, 1865-1917; 1.5; Archival Resource Key
    Found are scattered printed materials including exhibition catalogs for James D. Smillie, clippings, reproductions of works of art, and miscellanous art publications. Of note are advertisement circulars for engravings of Abraham Lincoln by William E. Marhsall and of President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation Before the Cabinet by F. B. Carpenter. Also found is a publishing proposal for a work by Bierstadt.
    - Exhibition Catalog (fragment), 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Exhibition Catalog, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clipping, 1901-1905; 1866; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - Reproductions of Works of Art, circa 1860s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Scope and Contents
      Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 4
    - Publishing Proposal, circa 1865; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
      For Picture of the Rocky Mountains by Albert Bierstadt.
    - Advertisement, 1866; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
      William E. Marshall's line engraving to Abraham Lincoln.
    - Advertisement, circa 1866; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
      F. B. Carpenter's President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation Before the Cabinet.
    - Art Publications, 1885-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Oversized Reproductions of Works of Art scanned with Box 5, Folder 6, circa 1860s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Art Publications scanned with Box 5, Folder 10, 1885-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Artwork, circa 1879; 1.6; Archival Resource Key
    Found is one etching by James D. Smillie entitled Up the Hill.
    - Etching, Up the Hill, circa 1879; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
- James Smillie Papers, 1882; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 5
  This series is comprised of writings and biographical material relating to James Smillie.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  2.1: Biographical Material, 1882
  2.2: Writings and Notes, 1882
  - Biographical Material, 2.1; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of memorabilia from James Smillie's and Catherine Van Valkenburg Smillie's 50th wedding anniversary in 1882 including an announcement, a poem to Catherine from James, a printed program, and a list of signatures of family members.
    - 50th Anniversary Memorabilia, James and Catherine Smillie, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Writings and Notes, 1882; 2.2; Archival Resource Key
    Found are copies of James Smillie's autobiography, A Pilgrimage, which includes an incomplete original copy written in James's hand, a photocopy of the complete original version, and a typescript.
    - A Pilgrimage, Incomplete, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - A Pilgrimage, Copies of Original, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - A Pilgrimage, Typescript, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
- George Smillie Papers, 1867-1920; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  The papers of George Henry Smillie include biographical material, correspondence, a scrapbook of clippings, printed materials, and portraits and snapshots of Smillie and his family.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries.
  3.1: Biographical Material, 1873-1921
  3.2: Correspondence, 1885-1925
  3.3: Scrapbook, 1867-1939
  3.4: Printed Material, 1872-1913
  3.5: Photographs, 1880-circa 1920
  - Biographical Material, 1873-1921; 3.1; Archival Resource Key
    Found is a biographical sketch, a business card from a company for which George worked, and membership certificates.
    - Biographical Sketch or Obituary, after 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Business Card, circa 1880s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Membership Certificates and Records, 1873-1883; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 1
    - Oversized Certificates from the National Academy of Design scanned with Box 5, Folder 18, 1883; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1885-1925; 3.2; Archival Resource Key
    The subseries consists of scattered correspondence between colleagues, friends, and family.
    - Halsey, R. T. H., 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hubbard, P. M. (?), 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Postcard of painted sign for the Bread Loaf Inn, designed by George Smillie in 1904.
    - S., R. O., 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Simpson, Nathaniel, 1885; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Secretary of American Art Association, announcing prize awarded to Smillie.
    - Smillie, William, 1903; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Unsigned and Illegible, circa 1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbook, 1867-1939; 3.3; Archival Resource Key
    Found is a scrapbook of clippings mostly pretaining to or written by George Henry Smillie.
    Materials that were loose inside the scrapbook are filed at the end and include clippings, reproductions of works of art, and periodicals.
    - Scrapbook of Clippings, circa 1867-1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
    - Clippings Tucked into Scrapbook, circa 1880s-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Reproductions of Works of Art and Periodicals Tucked into Scrapbook, circa 1880s-1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)